[
    {
        "question": "إِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "answer": "(of) Ibrahim",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 6,
        "tlit": "ib'rāhīma",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " صُحُفِ إِبْرَاهِيمَ وَمُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "Ibrahim",
        "waznTlit": "ib'rāhīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُؤْثِرُونَ",
        "answer": "You prefer",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 14,
        "tlit": "tu'thirūna",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ تُؤْثِرُونَ الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "أ ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آثَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to prefer",
        "waznTlit": "āthara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْآخِرَةُ",
        "answer": "While the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "154",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "wal-ākhiratu",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْآخِرَةُ خَيْرٌ وَأَبْقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "654",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَا شَاءَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ يَعْلَمُ الْجَهْرَ وَمَا يَخْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Exceptive particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "The One Who",
        "pcklId": "1413",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِي",
        "answer": "And the One Who",
        "pcklId": "1414",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِي قَدَّرَ فَهَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِي",
        "answer": "And the One Who",
        "pcklId": "1415",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِي أَخْرَجَ الْمَرْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "The one who",
        "pcklId": "1416",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يَصْلَى النَّارَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2832",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَا شَاءَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ يَعْلَمُ الْجَهْرَ وَمَا يَخْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "[the] former",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَفِي الصُّحُفِ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَبْقَىٰ",
        "answer": "and everlasting",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 150,
        "tlit": "wa-abqā",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْآخِرَةُ خَيْرٌ وَأَبْقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْقَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "remained",
        "waznTlit": "abqā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلَهُ",
        "answer": "And then makes it",
        "pcklId": "336",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalahu",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَهُ غُثَاءً أَحْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَتَجَنَّبُهَا",
        "answer": "And will avoid it",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 263,
        "tlit": "wayatajannabuhā",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَتَجَنَّبُهَا الْأَشْقَى",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَجَنَّبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avoid",
        "waznTlit": "yatajannabu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَهْرَ",
        "answer": "the manifest",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 270,
        "tlit": "l-jahra",
        "frequency": "16",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَا شَاءَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ يَعْلَمُ الْجَهْرَ وَمَا يَخْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ه ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَهْر",
        "waznEnglish": "publicizes",
        "waznTlit": "jahr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "dark",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 372,
        "tlit": "aḥwā",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَهُ غُثَاءً أَحْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "dark",
        "waznTlit": "aḥwā",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَحْيَىٰ",
        "answer": "will live",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "yaḥyā",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ لَا يَمُوتُ فِيهَا وَلَا يَحْيَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَىَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to live",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَيَاةَ",
        "answer": "the life",
        "pcklId": "170",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "l-ḥayata",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ تُؤْثِرُونَ الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَيَوٰة",
        "waznEnglish": "you will live",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَخْرَجَ",
        "answer": "brings forth",
        "pcklId": "150",
        "rootWordId": 397,
        "tlit": "akhraja",
        "frequency": "182",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِي أَخْرَجَ الْمَرْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخْرَجَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bring forth, to drive out",
        "waznTlit": "akhraja",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْشَىٰ",
        "answer": "fears (Allah)",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 410,
        "tlit": "yakhshā",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سَيَذَّكَّرُ مَنْ يَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَشِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fear",
        "waznTlit": "khashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَخْفَىٰ",
        "answer": "is hidden",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 425,
        "tlit": "yakhfā",
        "frequency": "34",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَا شَاءَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ يَعْلَمُ الْجَهْرَ وَمَا يَخْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ف ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَخْفَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hide",
        "waznTlit": "yakhfā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَ",
        "answer": "created",
        "pcklId": "175",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqa",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرٌ",
        "answer": "(is) better",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayrun",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْآخِرَةُ خَيْرٌ وَأَبْقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الدُّنْيَا",
        "answer": "(of) the world",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 488,
        "tlit": "l-dun'yā",
        "frequency": "133",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ تُؤْثِرُونَ الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "د ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُّنْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to draw",
        "waznTlit": "dun'yā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَذَكَرَ",
        "answer": "And remembers",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "wadhakara",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَذَكَرَ اسْمَ رَبِّهِ فَصَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remember, to mention",
        "waznTlit": "dhakara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَذَكِّرْ",
        "answer": "So remind",
        "pcklId": "100",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "fadhakkir",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَكِّرْ إِنْ نَفَعَتِ الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذُكِّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remind",
        "waznTlit": "dhukkira",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَيَذَّكَّرُ",
        "answer": "He will pay heed ",
        "pcklId": "151",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "sayadhakkaru",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَيَذَّكَّرُ مَنْ يَخْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to receive admonition",
        "waznTlit": "tadhakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the reminder",
        "pcklId": "194",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'rā",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَكِّرْ إِنْ نَفَعَتِ الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "944",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سَبِّحِ اسْمَ رَبِّكَ الْأَعْلَى",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) his Lord",
        "pcklId": "945",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَذَكَرَ اسْمَ رَبِّهِ فَصَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَرْعَىٰ",
        "answer": "the pasture",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 565,
        "tlit": "l-marʿā",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِي أَخْرَجَ الْمَرْعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَرْعَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and pasture",
        "waznTlit": "marʿā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "answer": "purifies (himself)",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 624,
        "tlit": "tazakkā",
        "frequency": "59",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " قَدْ أَفْلَحَ مَنْ تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ك و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "tazakkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبِّحِ",
        "answer": "Glorify",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "sabbiḥi",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَبِّحِ اسْمَ رَبِّكَ الْأَعْلَى",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَّحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to glorify, to praise",
        "waznTlit": "sabbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اسْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) name",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "is'ma",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " سَبِّحِ اسْمَ رَبِّكَ الْأَعْلَى",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اسْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) name",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "is'ma",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَذَكَرَ اسْمَ رَبِّهِ فَصَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "answer": "then proportioned",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "fasawwā",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي خَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fashion, to proportion",
        "waznTlit": "sawwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَشْقَى",
        "answer": "the wretched one",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 788,
        "tlit": "l-ashqā",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَتَجَنَّبُهَا الْأَشْقَى",
        "rootWord": "ش ق و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَشْقَى",
        "waznEnglish": "were wretched",
        "waznTlit": "ashqā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَاءَ",
        "answer": "wills",
        "pcklId": "235",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shāa",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَا شَاءَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ يَعْلَمُ الْجَهْرَ وَمَا يَخْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الصُّحُفِ",
        "answer": "the Scriptures",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 823,
        "tlit": "l-ṣuḥufi",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا لَفِي الصُّحُفِ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُحُف",
        "waznEnglish": "plates",
        "waznTlit": "ṣuḥuf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُحُفِ",
        "answer": "(The) Scriptures",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 823,
        "tlit": "ṣuḥufi",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " صُحُفِ إِبْرَاهِيمَ وَمُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُحُف",
        "waznEnglish": "plates",
        "waznTlit": "ṣuḥuf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَصَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and prays",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "faṣallā",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَذَكَرَ اسْمَ رَبِّهِ فَصَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pray, to bless",
        "waznTlit": "ṣallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَصْلَى",
        "answer": "will burn",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 858,
        "tlit": "yaṣlā",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يَصْلَى النَّارَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصْلَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to burn",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣlā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "knows",
        "pcklId": "375",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamu",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَا شَاءَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ يَعْلَمُ الْجَهْرَ وَمَا يَخْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَعْلَى",
        "answer": "the Most High",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "l-aʿlā",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " سَبِّحِ اسْمَ رَبِّكَ الْأَعْلَى",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "غُثَاءً",
        "answer": "stubble",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1050,
        "tlit": "ghuthāan",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَهُ غُثَاءً أَحْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ث و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غ ث و",
        "waznEnglish": "(as) rubbish of dead leaves",
        "waznTlit": "ghayn thā wāw",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفْلَحَ",
        "answer": "has succeeded",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1151,
        "tlit": "aflaḥa",
        "frequency": "40",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " قَدْ أَفْلَحَ مَنْ تَزَكَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ف ل ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَفْلَحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to succeed",
        "waznTlit": "aflaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّرَ",
        "answer": "measured",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qaddara",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِي قَدَّرَ فَهَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to determine, to plot",
        "waznTlit": "qaddara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَنُقْرِئُكَ",
        "answer": "We will make you recite",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "sanuq'ri-uka",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " سَنُقْرِئُكَ فَلَا تَنْسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نُقْرِئُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make recite",
        "waznTlit": "nuq'ri-u",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "[the] great",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kub'rā",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يَصْلَى النَّارَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُبْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kub'rā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَمُوتُ",
        "answer": "he will die",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "yamūtu",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ لَا يَمُوتُ فِيهَا وَلَا يَحْيَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to die",
        "waznTlit": "māta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَنْسَىٰ",
        "answer": "you will forget",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1469,
        "tlit": "tansā",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " سَنُقْرِئُكَ فَلَا تَنْسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن س ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَسِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to forget",
        "waznTlit": "nasiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفَعَتِ",
        "answer": "benefits",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1502,
        "tlit": "nafaʿati",
        "frequency": "50",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَكِّرْ إِنْ نَفَعَتِ الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to profit, to benifit",
        "waznTlit": "nafaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّارَ",
        "answer": "(in) the Fire",
        "pcklId": "137",
        "rootWordId": 1529,
        "tlit": "l-nāra",
        "frequency": "194",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِي يَصْلَى النَّارَ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَار",
        "waznEnglish": "a fire",
        "waznTlit": "nār",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَهَدَىٰ",
        "answer": "then guided",
        "pcklId": "141",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "fahadā",
        "frequency": "316",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالَّذِي قَدَّرَ فَهَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَدَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to guide",
        "waznTlit": "hadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنُيَسِّرُكَ",
        "answer": "And We will ease you",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "wanuyassiruka",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنُيَسِّرُكَ لِلْيُسْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْيُسْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "to the ease",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "lil'yus'rā",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "87",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنُيَسِّرُكَ لِلْيُسْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُسْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "We (have) made it easy",
        "waznTlit": "yus'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    }
]